MEHUL SEN

Rochester, New York · +1-585-298-7647 · mehulsen@mail.rit.edu · mehulsen.com · linkedIn.com/in/mehulsen

CompTIA Security+ and Network+ certified M.S. student in cybersecurity specializing in network security, vulnerability assessments, machine learning applications in cybersecurity and development of security tools.

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, NY

- Master of Science in Cybersecurity GPA 3.9/4.0, May 2024
- Bachelor of Science in Cybersecurity Summa cum laude, December 2022

SKILLS & CERTIFICATIONS

Technical Skills: Cybersecurity Fundamentals, Network Security, Vulnerability Assessments, Risk Analysis, Penetration Testing, Incident Response, Threat Intelligence, Python/Bash Scripting, SIEM and SOAR Management, OSINT, Metadata Analysis, Reverse Engineering, PCI/SOX, HIPAA and GDPR Compliance, Cryptography, System Administration, AI and Machine Learning, Offensive Security

Certifications: CompTIA Security+ (January 2024), Network+ (July 2022), Machine Learning Specialization (Coursera, January 2023)), Summer Learning Academy Externship (AT&T, July 2021)

Competitions: BSidesROC CTF 2024, Red Team (RIT's IRSec 2020), Blue Team (ISTS 17 and UB's Lockdown v5), Hackathons (Brickhack V and Brickhack VI)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Wegmans Food Markets, Rochester, NY

January 2022 – August 2022

Network Support Technician Co-op

- Collaborated with network engineers to configure and troubleshoot various network devices, including Cisco and Arista routers, POLRE Phybridges, Raritan switches, wireless bridges, Palo Alto firewalls, Digi modems, and Cisco Jabber, ensuring robust organization-wide connectivity and direct support for employee network issues using Solarwinds Orion and BMC SmartIT, boosting operational efficiency.
- Configured and deployed network infrastructure for new locations, essential for expansion by establishing solid network foundations.
- **Developed and optimized tools for automating network configuration and troubleshooting processes**, reducing device configuration and deployment time across new and existing locations and significantly reducing configuration and troubleshooting time for connectivity issues.

Value Point Systems, Bengaluru, India

July 2019 – August 2019

Security Operations Center Intern

- **Designed and deployed a brute-force detection playbook on the SOAR platform** (Demisto), integrating with IBM QRadar and Active Directory for enhanced threat detection. This playbook analyzes user login history and actions, streamlining the identification of brute-force attacks for faster response and remediation.
- **Developed custom scripts in Python to handle and analyze large datasets.** These scripts enabled the SOAR platform to process login attempts and flag suspicious activities efficiently, significantly improving the threat-hunting process by reducing manual data analysis and accelerating threat detection.
- **Executed comprehensive OSINT and vulnerability assessments,** pinpointing potential security vulnerabilities and information leaks. Generated detailed reports with actionable mitigation, strengthening security measures and enhancing the organization's security posture.

PROJECTS

Machine Learning applications in Cybersecurity

August 2023 – December 2023

Developed advanced machine learning models to improve cybersecurity measures. Some of my notable projects include deep neural networks to detect deepfakes, analyze anomalous traffic, spam and malicious traffic. I have also designed adversarial machine learning models that focus on generating and defending against malicious attacks. Additionally, I have expertise in designing website fingerprinting models using deep neural networks.

Triangulation Approach for Imminent Threat Detection

January 2023 – May 2023

Partnered with the U.S. Department of State Diplomatic Security Service through the Hacking for Diplomacy (H4D) program to enhance embassy security. Coordinated stakeholder interviews (over 50 participants), designed and implemented a triangulation-based solution for rapid threat detection, and improved emergency response protocols.

Vulnerability Assessment of Trillium Health

August 2022 - December 2022

Directed a thorough cybersecurity audit for Trillium Health, incorporating OSINT, metadata analysis, threat modeling, and social engineering tests. Delivered comprehensive reports with actionable insights, significantly enhancing the organization's cybersecurity posture.